Yong-Han Lin (she/her)

★ https://yonghanlin.github.io | ✓ yon9hanlin@gmail.com

Research Interests

My past research experience in developing and evaluating a more intelligent smartphone notification system led to my interest in investigating the challenges in people's interactions with and reliance on automated systems. Specifically, I am interested in 1) enhancing user autonomy when interacting with automated systems, and 2) designing adaptive automated technologies that cater to personalized needs in diverse contexts.

Areas of interest: Human-Computer Interaction; Human-centered Al; User Empowerment

Education

National Yang-Ming Chiao-Tung University* (NYCU)

B.S. in Computer Science

Sept. 2018 - June 2022 Hsinchu, Taiwan

- Overall GPA: 3.84/4.3 | Major GPA: 3.91/4.3 | Last 60 Credits: 4.07/4.3
- **Selected Coursework**: Data Structures, Database Systems, Operating Systems, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, User Experience & Usability Evaluation, CSCW Research Summer Institute

Research Experience

NYCU Mobile and Ubiquitous Interaction Lab, Undergraduate Research Assistant Advisor: Dr. Yung-Ju (Stanley) Chang

July 2022 - May 2024 Hsinchu, Taiwan

- Conducted studies using the experience-sampling method (ESM), diaries, and interviews to investigate users' perceptions of automatic, manual, and hybrid notification management methods, and the findings resulted in a first-author full paper submission to 2024 IMWUT [J.1] and a poster presented at the 2023 UbiComp/ISWC conference [P.1]
- Led 3 college students and 1 graduate student to research and build an Android notification system that provides automatic sorting and categorization capabilities by the implementation of the BERT model and Flask, while also enabling manually pin, sort, and categorize notifications [project site]
- Employed thematic analysis to identify users' strategies for customizing mobile notification alerts, and the findings resulted in a full paper submission to 2024 MobileHCI conference [C.3]
- Researched and conducted mixed-methods analysis on users' notification interactions in multi-device environments, and the findings resulted in a paper at the 2023 CHI conference [C.2]

Polytechnique Montreal Human-Centered Design Lab, Research Intern

Advisor: Dr. Jinghui Cheng

June 2021 – Jan. 2022 Remote

• Conducted a qualitative content analysis and a statistical analysis to understand the usage, purposes, and impacts of visual artifacts in GitHub issue tracker system, the findings resulted in a paper at the 2022 EASE conference [C.1]

Peer-Reviewed Publications

(* indicates equal contribution)

[J.1] Pinning, Sorting, and Categorizing Notifications: A Mixed-methods Usage and Experience Study of Mobile Notification-management Features [paper link][project site]

Yong-Han Lin, Li-Ting Su, Uei-Dar Chen, Yi-Chi Lee, Peng-Jui Wang, Yung-Ju Chang. In submission to ACM IMWUT '24 (R&R Cycle)

[C.3] "I Want Lower Tone for Work-Related Notifications": Exploring the Effectiveness of User-Assigned Notification Alerts in Improving User Speculation of and Attendance to Mobile Notifications [paper link]

Tang-Jie Chang, Li-Ting Su, **Yong-Han Lin**, Jie Tsai, Zi-Xun Tang, Yung-Ju Chang. In submission to ACM MobileHCI '24 (R&R Cycle)

[P.1] Automatic, Manual, or Hybrid? A Preliminary Investigation of Users' Perception of Features for Supporting Notification Management [paper link][project site]

Yong-Han Lin, Li-Ting Su, Uei-Dar Chen, Peng-Jui Wang, Yi-Chi Lee, Yung-Ju Chang. In *Adjunct Proceedings of the 2023 ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing & the 2023 ACM International Symposium on Wearable*

^{*}Former name: National Chiao-Tung University (NCTU)

Computing (UbiComp/ISWC '23), pp. 98-102.

[C.2] Multiple Device Users' Actual and Ideal Cross-device Usage for Multi-Stage Notification-Interactions: An ESM Study Addressing the Usage Gap and Impacts of Device Context [paper link]

Fang-Ching Tseng, Zih-Yun Chiou, Ho-Hsuan Chuang, Li-Ting Su, **Yong-Han Lin**, Yu-Rou Lin, Yi-Chi Lee, Peng-Jui Wang, Uei-Dar Chen, Yung-Ju Chang. In *Proceedings of the 2023 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems* **(CHI '23)**, pp. 1-15.

[C.1] Understanding the Characteristics of Visual Contents in Open Source Issue Discussions [paper link]

Vishakha Agrawal*, **Yong-Han Lin***, Jinghui Cheng. In *Proceedings of the 26th International Conference on Evaluation and Assessment in Software Engineering* **(EASE '22)**, pp. 249-254.

Teaching Experience

Teaching Assistant

NYCU CS 1270: Introduction to Database Systems (Spring 2022)

Instructor: Dr. Yi-Ju Tseng

Course Assistant

NYCU General Education: Critical and Creative Thinking (Spring 2021)

Instructor: Dr. Jonathon Hricko

Honors and Awards

Cornell, Maryland, Max-Planck Pre-doctoral Research School Invitation (Summer 2024)

Awarded a travel grant to participate in person at Max-Planck Institute to learn about cutting-edge research in computer science

Taiwan National Science and Technology Council Research Grant Award (Fall 2021)

Awarded a grant for doing research on studying users' perception of automatic and manual notification management methods

Polytechnique Montreal Research Internship Scholarship (Summer 2021)

Awarded a scholarship for doing research on improving the usability of scientific open source software

Volunteer and Leadership

Student Volunteer

CHI 2023, Hamburg

Provided support for paper session, hybrid Zoom meeting, and exhibit hall

CSCW 2022, Virtual

Monitored paper presentation video on YouTube livestream, and provided quick responses in GatherTown

Team Leader in Public Relation

Mei-Chu Hackathon 2020

Led a team of 6 students to contact corporate sponsorship and received 40K+ USD from Google, Amazon, etc

Industry Experience

Software Engineering Intern

Xaduro Inc. (travel tech startup)

Jan. 2021 – June 2021

Taipei, Taiwan

- Collaborated with the engineering team to develop a travel agency system that allows 1K+ users by using MySQL, PHP, and JavaScript [project site]
- Optimized the hotel reservation system by fixing 80% of the usability issues detected from Google Search Console

Skills

Programming: Python, HTML/CSS/JavaScript, Java, C++/C, R, SQL

Software and Tools: Android, Git, Firebase, Flask, Linux, LTEX

Last updated: May 28, 2024 2/2